peoplematter.com 2015-04-25

# PeopleMatter Privacy and Security Policies | PeopleMatter

PeopleMatter respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal information. This Policy governs the use of our website [www.peoplematter.com](http://www.peoplematter.com/) and our online products and services. This Policy incorporates by reference the Terms of Use for PeopleMatter’s website and services, which can be accessed upon request by contacting [support@peoplematter.com](mailto:support@peoplematter.com). 

In this Policy, we describe the information that we collect; how we use, disclose and share your information; and how we protect your information. This Policy applies to all visitors to our website, including viewers of our website, job applicants, and prospective employers. Unless we distinguish among job applicants, prospective employers, and other visitors to our website, the practices described herein apply to all of our visitors.

PeopleMatter provides an innovative job seeking solution through which we connect interested people with potential employers. As part of this process, we collect information, including personal information, from people who apply for jobs through our online job application. In this Policy we describe the information that we collect from people seeking jobs, who we refer to as “job applicants” as well as from the third party companies posting jobs, which we refer to as “job posters” or “potential employers.”

### Information We Collect

We may collect information about you from a variety of sources, including information we collect from you directly when you apply for a job or post an open position; information we collect about you when you visit our site, use our services, view our online advertisements; and information we collect about you from other sources, such as third party partners and affiliates (where permitted by law).

#### Information We Collect Directly From Job Applicants and Other Visitors to Our Website

We collect information directly from you, including personal information, when you visit our website, apply for a job through our online product, register for an email subscription, create an account on our website, update your profile on your account, request information from us, or choose to complete our surveys or questionnaires (either online or paper). 

We may collect this information from you at different phases of the employment search process; in other words, you may submit certain limited information when you create an account with us; additional information to apply for a position; and if hired, you may submit additional information. The following are examples of information that we may collect directly from you through your voluntary submission:

  * Name, email address and postal address
  * Username and password
  * Date of birth
  * Phone number or mobile number
  * Company name, job title, company website
  * Driver’s license number
  * Social security number
  * Ethnic origin
  * Interests
  * Products/services in which you have expressed an interest
  * Biographical information, such as employment history, educational history or any other information that you choose to submit to us
  * Information that may be contained in a resume that you choose to voluntarily submit to us
  * Additional information requested by the prospective employer

You do not have to provide us with any personal information to view our website, and you are permitted to browse job postings anonymously. If you choose to become a registered user, you will be required to submit name and contact information. If you choose to apply for a particular job, you may be required to provide additional information, such as the information listed in the bullet points above.

If your application is accepted, you may be required to provide additional information so that we can conduct a background check or determine employer tax credit eligibility. In each case, we will collect only the personal information from you that you chose to provide to us. If you chose not to provide certain information, however, then we may be unable to provide you with all of the features of our online product, such as applying for jobs.

#### Information We Collect Directly From Prospective Employers

We collect information directly from you, including personal information, when you visit our website, post an open position, create an account on our website, update your profile on your account, request information from us, or choose to complete our surveys or questionnaires (either online or paper). The following are examples of information that we may collect from you:

  * Name, email address and postal address
  * Username and password
  * Date of birth
  * Phone number or mobile number
  * Company name, job title, company website
  * Open positions within your company
  * Bank and/or financial information

#### Information We Collect When You Visit Our Site

We use cookies and other technologies to collect information about you when you visit our site and use our services. Specifically, we may collect the following information via these technologies:

  * Your browser type and operating system
  * Web pages you view
  * Links you click
  * IP address
  * Site visited before coming to our site

#### Information We Collect From Other Sources

We may obtain information about you, either individually or in the aggregate, from other sources, such as third party partners and affiliates, including, but not limited to, the following:

  * Name, email address, postal address
  * Birth date
  * Usage patterns regarding visitors to our website

PeopleMatter is not responsible for the accuracy of this information.

### How We Use The Information We Collect About You

#### Job Applicants and Other Visitors to Our Website

We use the information that we collect about you for several general purposes: to submit your application for an employment opportunity; to notify you of potential employment opportunities; to facilitate your hiring if your application is accepted; to fulfill your requests for services and products; to fulfill your requests for information about our services and products; and to inform you about the latest product developments and other information from us or from our business partners that we believe would be of interest to you. Specifically, we use the information that we collect about you for the following purposes, as applicable:

  * To submit a job application to a third party
  * To conduct a background check
  * To determine employer tax credit eligibility
  * To create and manage your account
  * Where permitted by law, to provide you with customized offers and information about our products and services
  * To develop and provide products and services tailored to your interests
  * To enable a prospective employer to process the necessary paperwork so that a new employee can begin employment
  * To enforce our terms and conditions and otherwise manage our business

#### Employers

We use the information that we collect about you for several general purposes: to fulfill your requests for services and products; to fulfill your requests for information about our services and products; and to inform you about the latest product developments and other information from us or from our business partners that we believe would be of interest to you. Specifically, we use the information that we collect about you for the following purposes, as applicable:

  * To determine tax credit eligibility
  * To create and manage your account
  * To fulfill your order for our services (including payment processing)
  * Where permitted by law, to provide you with customized offers and information about our products and services
  * To develop and provide products and services tailored to your interests
  * To enforce our terms and conditions and otherwise manage our business

### Opting Out of Marketing Communications

We may send you promotional email messages if you request to receive information from us via email. You may stop receiving promotional email messages by following the information contained in the email message or by completing the opt-out [form](http://success.peoplematter.com/l/20162/2013-10-01/6nnty).

### Job Applications for Positions with PeopleMatter

In addition to our online product, PeopleMatter also will collect personal information through our website at [www.peoplematter.com](http://www.peoplematter.com/) for open positions with our own company. Applicants for PeopleMatter positions will be required to submit their name, mailing and email address, phone number, job history, and a resume. When you apply for a job with PeopleMatter, we use your information only for the purpose of fulfilling your job application with PeopleMatter. We may share your information with third parties to process your application or to conduct a credit check.

### Updating Your Personal Information

You may modify information that you provided to us when you created your account (name, email address, user ID and password) by logging into your [account](https://peoplematter.at/).

### Sharing Your Information

#### Job Applicant Information

We share job applicant information, at your request and direction, with prospective employers. We also share job applicant information, after you have consented, to third parties for the purposes, as applicable, of conducting background checks and to determine whether the employer is eligible for tax credits. Once an applicant has been hired, we also may share additional information with your employer for payroll or other administrative functions.

#### All Personal Information (Job Applicants, Employers and Other Website Visitors)

We may hire vendor companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as payment processing, sending postal and electronic mail, providing technical support, and to assist us in providing the products and services that you request from us. We only provide those service providers with the information necessary to perform the requested service.

We also may engage in joint marketing activities with third parties. If we do so, then we give you an opportunity to opt out of such information sharing.

We do not sell, lease, or rent your information to other companies or individuals. PeopleMatter however, reserves the right to disclose your information if it licenses, sells, or otherwise transfers its technology or business, or a portion thereof, to third parties.

We also may disclose your personal information to protect our rights and property, to prevent against fraud and abuse, and to protect other users of our services. We also may disclose your information as permitted or required by law.

### Security of Your Information

We want the information that you submit to us to be secure. We use industry-standard techniques to safeguard the information that you provide to us through our server. Notwithstanding our commitment to your information, please be aware that there is a risk that others could find a way to thwart our security systems. As a result, we cannot ensure or warrant the security or privacy of any information that you choose to submit to us.

### User-Generated Content

Portions of our website permit users to submit their own content for blogs or to respond to blog postings. PeopleMatter is not responsible for the privacy of any information that you choose to submit through a public forum, such as a blog, or for the accuracy of any information contained in those postings. Any information that you disclose becomes public information. We cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy.

### Children’s Privacy

This website and our products and services are not intended for use by children. PeopleMatter does not accept job applicants from children under the age of 13 and does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.

### Cookies

Cookies are small, digital signature files that are stored by your Web browser that allow your preferences to be recorded when visiting a Web site. They may also be used to track your return visits to the Web site.

Third-party advertising companies may also use cookies for tracking purposes.

### Google Ads

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads.

Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to visitors based on their visits to sites they frequent on the Internet.

Website visitors may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Advertising and Privacy policy [webpage](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads).

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We will post changes to this Policy to this website. Changes will become effective upon posting. If we make a material change to this Policy, then we will highlight that change upon posting.

### Contact Us

Please contact us at [support@peoplematter.com](mailto:support@peoplematter.com) if you have any questions regarding this Policy.

 _Effective Date: 03.30.2011_
